Guide to the Don Chenoweth Papers TAM.216
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Don Chenoweth Papers
circa 1920s-1960s
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Chenoweth, Leslie
Chenoweth, Don
TAM.216
10 Linear Feet in 8 record cartons and 4 manuscript boxes.
Donald J. Chenoweth was a socialist activist. This collection contains material from multiple socialist organizations he was involved with from the 1930s through the 1950s, including the Independent Socialist League, the Socialist Workers Party, the Workers Party, and the Young People's Socialist League.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Materials were donated by Leslie Chenoweth in 1999. The accession number associated with this gift is 1950.169.
Biographical Note
Donald J. Chenoweth was a socialist activist and member of the Independent Socialist League, and of other progressive collections.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains material including minutes, internal memos, circulars, publications, and correspondence of American socialist groups including the Independent Socialist League, the Socialist Workers Party, the Workers Party, and the Young People's Socialist League. Also part of the collection are articles, magazines, and other publications on topics related to socialism and, especially, Trotskyism, mostly from the 1930s- early 1950s.
Separated Materials
Books donated by Leslie Chenoweth were separated to the Library collection.
Arrangement
This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.
Socialism -- United States -- 20th century.; Socialism -- United States -- Newspapers.; Socialism -- United States -- Periodicals.; Trotskyism -- United States.; Chenoweth, Leslie; Socialist Workers Party; Independent Socialist League; Workers Party (1940-1949); Young People's Socialist League
- Pamphlets, Magazines, Bulletins, Article drafts, circa 1930s-1950s (Box 1)
- Publications, Pamphlets, Article drafts, Notes, Manuscripts, circa 1930s-1960s (Box 2)
- Pamphlets, Article drafts, Correspondence, Articles, Bulletins, circa 1930s-1940s (Box 3)
- Bulletins, Circulars, Correspondence, Minutes, Publications, circa 1930s-1950s (Box 4)
- Correspondence, Minutes, Circulars, circa 1940s-1950s (Box 5)
- Minutes, Notes, Magazines, Newspapers, circa 1940s-1950s (Box 6)
- Correspondence, Minutes, Memos, Bulletins, circa 1940s-1950s (Box 7)
- Correspondence, Minutes, Memos, Bulletins, circa 1940s-1950s (Box 8)
- Publications, Pamphlets, circa 1920s-1950s (Box 9)
- Publications, Pamphlets, circa 1920s-1950s (Box 10)
- Publications, Pamphlets, Newspapers, Article drafts, Correspondence, circa 1920s-1950s (Box 11)
- Drafts, Circulars, Bulletins, Magazines, circa 1920s-1950s (Box 12)